<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<info:toolkitInfoModel xmlns:common="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/common" xmlns:info="http://www.ibm.com/xmlns/prod/streams/spl/toolkitInfo">
  <info:identity>
    <info:name>com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage</info:name>
    <info:description>
The Object Storage toolkit is an open source IBM Streams toolkit that helps you integrate IBM Streams with IBM Cloud Object Storage.

The operators provide the ability for IBM Streams applications to write objects to object storage and read objects from object storage.

The operators support IBM Cloud Object Storage and S3 compatible object storages.

The Object Storage toolkit operators must be configured to connect to S3 compatible object storages. This configuration information needs to be specified with operator parameters.

The toolkit contains two namespaces:

* com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage
* com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage.s3

Operators in the `com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage` use generic parameters approach rather the operators in the `com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage.s3` namespace use S3-compliant authentication and connection parameters.
For example, `ObjectStorageSink` uses `objectStorageURI` parameter which consists of protocol and bucket name (s3a://&lt;BUCKET_NAME&gt;/), rather `S3ObjectStorageSink` operator uses S3-compliant parameter names such as protocol and bucket as a separate parameters making it more intuitive for the users familiar with S3 COS terms.
Note, that other operator parameter groups (except of authentication and connection) are exactly the same for both operators.

+ Developing and running applications that use the ObjectStorage Toolkit

To create applications that use the ObjectStorage Toolkit, you must configure either Streams Studio
or the SPL compiler to be aware of the location of the toolkit. 

# Before you begin

* Install IBM Streams. Configure the product environment variables by entering the following command: 
      &lt;source product-installation-root-directory>/&lt;your version>/bin/streamsprofile.sh


# About this task

After the location of the toolkit is communicated to the compiler, the SPL artifacts that are specified in the toolkit
can be used by an application. The application can include a use directive to bring the necessary namespaces into scope.
Alternatively, you can fully qualify the operators that are provided by toolkit with their namespaces as prefixes.

# Procedure

1. Review the list of restrictions for the IBM Streams specialized toolkits in the product documentation.
2. Configure the SPL compiler to find the toolkit root directory. Use one of the following methods:
  * Set the **STREAMS_SPLPATH** environment variable to the root directory of a toolkit or multiple toolkits (with : as a separator).
    For example:
        export STREAMS_SPLPATH=$STREAMS_INSTALL/toolkits/com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage
  * Specify the **-t** or **--spl-path** command parameter when you run the **sc** command. For example:
        sc -t $STREAMS_INSTALL/toolkits/com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage -M MyMain
    where MyMain is the name of the SPL main composite.
    **Note**: These command parameters override the **STREAMS_SPLPATH** environment variable.
  * Add the toolkit location in Streams Studio.
3. Develop your application. To avoid the need to fully qualify the operators, add a use directive in your application. 
  * For example, you can add the following clause in your SPL source file:
        use com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage::*;
    You can also specify a use clause for individual operators by replacing the asterisk (\*) with the operator name. For example: 
        use com.ibm.streamsx.objectstorage::ObjectStorageSink; 
4. Build your application. You can use the **sc** command or Streams Studio.  
5. Start the IBM Streams instance. 
6. Run the application. You can submit the application as a job by using the **streamtool submitjob** command or by using Streams Studio. 

</info:description>
    <info:version>1.3.0</info:version>
    <info:requiredProductVersion>4.2.0.0</info:requiredProductVersion>
  </info:identity>
  <info:dependencies/>
</info:toolkitInfoModel>
